IRIN NAHAR

Scarborough, 4372201109

Skype: live:.cid.a637296efc7407eb **Email**: <u>irinnahar13@gmail.com</u>

Summary:

I have been working as a Front end Developer over the last 3 years. I have been developing and designing software and websites with various programming languages. Developing creative things and enjoying challenges is my passion. Through my practical work, I have leveled up my skills in Software designing & development by using the cutting edge technology. Therefore, I want to work for those companies who care about talents & hard working.

Skills

Proficient: HTML5, CSS3, Sass, Bootstrap, Materialize, Angular Material, Angular 7, ES6, Typescript, Javascript,
AWS(s3 bucket, cognito), C#, Cross-browser compatibility, responsive web design, Wordpress, Photoshop

Familiar : React, MySQL.

Profile:

GitHub: https://github.com/Irinnahar

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/irinnahar/

Education:

Centennial College: Diploma in Software Engineering Technology(On-going)

BRAC University: BSC in Computer Science & Engineering

Work Experience:

Walmart, Pickering, Canada, Cashier and Customer Service

July 2020 - Present

- Handle cash, credit or check transactions with customers.
- Resolve customer complaints, guide them and provide relevant information.
- Make sales referrals, cross-sell products and introduce new one.

Graaho, Dhaka, Bangladesh, Front End Developer

September 2018 - February 2020

Responsibility:

- Working with all the latest front end technology such as HTML5, CSS3, SASS, Bootstrap 4, Materialize, Angular Material.
- Working with SPA Framework mainly on Angular 7 partially on React. Also worked on Django a little bit.
- Working with latest Javascript features, ES6, Typescript, Rest Api.
- Familiar with AWS S3 bucket and cognito user authentication.
- Took concepts and produced design mockups and prototypes to strengthen designs, enhance user experiences and improve site interactions.
- Convert PSD into pixel perfect UI with HTML and CSS

Projects:

- https://khaodao.com
- https://excesstoneeds.org
- https://www.graaho.com

Rapid Technology, Dhaka, Bangladesh, Front End Developer

May 2017-August 2018

Responsibility:

- Design web applications with the latest Front End Technologies such as HTML5, CSS, SASS, Angular material, google material, bootstrap, AngularJS, Angular typescript, and JavaScript.
- For this project, we use Git, Grunt, Gulp, and Bower.
- Converting Photoshop layouts to web pages, estimate time, and determine client's requirements and specifications.
- Work with senior back-end developers to solve large, complex design features for front-end challenges that meet requirements specifications.
- Collaborate with graphics designers to ensure the technical feasibility of UI/UX designs. Carry out quality assurance tests to discover errors and optimize usability.
- Wok with Photoshop, illustrator, Adobe XD, InvisionApp
- Write maintainable, scalable, responsive, consistency in design and layout, and cross browser code.
- Follow agile methodology by using Jira, Trello

Projects: www.seebiz.com (Contribution to front end, Mean stack)

Trenza Software, Dhaka, Bangladesh, Web Developer (Intern)

August 2016- February 2017

Responsibility

- Build client websites with WordPress. Modify existing code as needed.
- Work with the QA Department on a customized testing plan.
- Develop themes.
- Website and Web Application Development Coding of custom WordPress theme and template files using HTML, CSS, PHP, and Bootstrap.
- Worked on Magneto, Big commerce. Convert PSD to webpage by HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.
- Worked on big Commerce, Shopify, Open cart customize theme development

Projects:

- https://www.powermedicalsupplies.com/
- http://www.adeptnetworks.com
- https://mapiac.com/
- http://adventurewild.com.au

"I certify that all information stated in this CV is true and complete to the best of my knowledge and belief"